<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vedarth&#39;s Journal</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vedarth&#39;s Journal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 16:11:53 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/journal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Bench With Rusted Handle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/general/thebenchwithrustedhandle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 16:11:53 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/general/thebenchwithrustedhandle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;its past 5 pm and a man enters the park walking to a bench mechanically as if that man was coming everyday to that bench, he must have developed a sense of ownership of that wooden old bench with a partially rusted metal handle. he sits on one side taking only space he needed, he sat as if even anyone passing from that bench would feel invited yet puts his bag so carelessly a bit away from where it could possibly touch him, as if he knows that no one in eternity is ever coming on that bench to join him. he catches his breath without extra activities like loosing his tie and pull his collar or any such activity that would express his tiresome job so extravagantly he just sits there normally and makes himself now more comfortable putting his hand on rusted handle and laying his head down on whatever space the width of bench&amp;rsquo;s support provided. he looks at the fading sky without a blink for it had also became a habit for him to watch the sky irrespective of its state it mattered little to him whether the sky was fading or rising, and not a single thing he had done since he came in the park was out of his regular routine. definitely he never imagined himself making a routine of anything let alone something he would consciously do in order to gain some peace. he truly had nothing but a great imitation of energy you would get from a person who is robbed of everything. but no one, no one in world could know that just by looking at him once acknowledging him as a person like normally people would do in park, for the very little presence he was holding among children playing in front of him and people walking and talking around all the places they found themselves comfortable in, for them this simple man was the same comfortable in his own place who mustn&amp;rsquo;t be disturbed by getting involved with him in any way, he came here to sit for a while must&amp;rsquo;ve been had a hard day at work let the man have some peace. well not that any of the parties present there the man or the people and children were complaining, it all felt so natural to everyone haha what do you even call natural, everyone shaped their minds that this park was indeed in its equilibrium state where whatever it presented must be considered all natural.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Existance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/journal/existance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 16:06:54 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/journal/existance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If I can read this I still exist. If I can hear this I still exist. for I can think of this I still exist.&#xA;the sole Existence the very own entity that I can call my own it exists with me because of me and dies with me. its my complex awareness wordified in somewhat readable and understandable form to some extent the authenticity of it purely depends on my ability to write, my vocabulary at given point of time when a word is written here or replaced here, that word, it could be word from English Gujarati Sanskrit Hindi Japanese Dictionary or created by me for that particular position of my writing  since if this is my try to express something this delicate I want it to be the prefect to each detail exactly the way I want , the structure of sentence, I write any language as I please in order to preserve its meaning its authenticity, I want every word I wrote here to emit the exact energy, meaning, tone shape, position, idea exactly the way it originally occurred to me or as much similar as it can be to that state when I wrote it. everything I write here I can call it my own regardless of its first use since that word exists because I positioned it I choose it to be there so I call it my own, that word has meaning what I gave it in my writings weather it matches with its original meaning or not so I see myself as an Owner of that word since anything I wrote here has any meaning only because I as Vedarth took the instance of that word and its meaning game a place in my mind and made it way to express something that I own language is not generalized but and individual system that each language understanding being tries to make their own version of it and makes a set of words and its meaning the way they understand, that sat of meaning collides with another language understanding being on wish of the first being, the intersection of that vocabulary(here pair of word and its meaning combined) is the possible way for one to have any way to communicate to the other and unfortunately the second array &amp;ldquo;the meaning of word&amp;rdquo; also happens to be individual so it boils down to only words in a language could be in that intersection of two person&amp;rsquo;s scope of communication. lastly the third one observing the two complete sets its intersections may still not get a whole view due to his own meaning of words so in conclusion NO BEING having language as a way to communicate would ever be able to understand another so it is 100% possible that if you are anyone else then the Vedarth who wrote this would never ever be able to understand any of it the way I THE VEDARTH was able to understand, feel, express and therefore this thing also dies with me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Substraction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/devlog/substraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 12:09:14 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/devlog/substraction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was wondering what should I put in devlogs since I have already coded most of the core mechenics, and well forcing myself to write isn&amp;rsquo;t how I wanna do this, so I put hold to this whole website making phase and continued my devlopment.&lt;br&gt;&#xA; &lt;br&gt;&#xA;I was to design and work on implementing Journal in a room and also a letterbox outside what I call Crimson Mansion and there I created these walls for room and trees so the letter box doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel so lonely.&lt;br&gt;&#xA; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 01:43:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/about/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crimson Square</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/devlog/crimsonsquare/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 01:39:26 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/devlog/crimsonsquare/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A quentized figment of human consiousness randered into a game&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;now as I am writing it here this tagline feels so flashy lol&lt;br&gt;&#xA; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;after banging my head to pc for 3 years to learn basic Game Devlopment I remembered why was I learing it in the first place.&lt;br&gt;&#xA; &lt;br&gt;&#xA;Games are after all final form of &lt;strong&gt;art&lt;/strong&gt; they combine &lt;strong&gt;Art, Writing, Music&lt;/strong&gt; All sorts of practices that fall under &lt;strong&gt;art&lt;/strong&gt; you can put that into a game.&lt;br&gt;&#xA; &lt;br&gt;&#xA;well around same time I stumbled upon a game I used to play Knytt Stories its a free game created by Swidish Game Devloper&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nifflas&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Nicklas Nygren (Nicklas)&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA; &lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://egomassive.com/ks/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;you can get/see it here&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA; &lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nifflas.fandom.com/wiki/Knytt&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Knytt wiki&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA; &lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.rockpapershotgun.com/images/sept07/knytt2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lol&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and man its a beautiful game with VAAAAAAAST world as its name suggests&#xA;Knytt (which roughly translates as &amp;ldquo;tiny creature&amp;rdquo; in Swedish) the world feels so huge and explorable in this game that I spent hours, I can go in any direction and most fascinating part was world was alive without me as a player, the in game creatures lived there and that felt quite amusing to watch creatures looking like humans live underground catching fishes in lava and 2 brothers fighting somewhere on shores of some river created from a waterfall thats located under the ocean man as vauge as this sounds I found it really cool it had a unique level design and artstyle to it that I haven&amp;rsquo;t played something like that in all these years playing countless games.&lt;br&gt;&#xA; &lt;br&gt;&#xA;I wanted to create something like that, I wanted to tell something &lt;strong&gt;Knytt way&lt;/strong&gt; but well ofcourse being new to game devlopment reproducing that level of quality and polishing was wayy ahead of me. and thus born something broken and Originally named Bobba Square lol but renamed to &lt;strong&gt;Crimson Square&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA; &lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;../../blogImages/CrimsonSquare/CrimsonSquarebig.png&#34; alt=&#34;Crimson Square&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Static Sites With Hugo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/devlog/buildingstaticsiteswithhugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 01:50:15 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/devlog/buildingstaticsiteswithhugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Start by installing HUGO (ofc)&lt;br&gt;&#xA; &lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://gohugo.io/&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA; &lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/installation/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://gohugo.io/installation/&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA; &lt;br&gt;&#xA;After installation you can verify if its working by typing&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-cmd&#34; data-lang=&#34;cmd&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;hugo version&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hope that shows something like this instead of error&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-cmd&#34; data-lang=&#34;cmd&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;hugo v0.143.1-0270364a347b2ece97e0321782b21904db515ecc+extendedwindows/amd64 BuildDate=2025-02-04T08:57:38Z VendorInfo=gohugoio  &#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;and I presume you have a git installed already just like a normal insane person who doesn&amp;rsquo;t wanna use blogger or medium but just in case&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/downloads&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://git-scm.com/downloads&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xA; &lt;br&gt;&#xA;so after that&#xA;go to the directory where you wish to create the website this command will make a root folder for itself so you just have to go somewhere like documents and create a template by writing&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Built This</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/journal/devlog/whyibuiltthis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 01:50:15 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/journal/devlog/whyibuiltthis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am Working on a Game called &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crimson Square&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and for a long time I wanted to make a structured wall of how the game was coming up and what progress I was making for my own refrence.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I would normally use &lt;a href=&#34;https://obsidian.md/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA; or Word for something like this(ofc) but then I thought what point would it serve if not published? I could go with &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA; or google&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blogger.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Blogger&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA; which would let me write and publish blogs for free but (heh) none of them provide complete customization of the way I wanted to render my blogs/devlogs, so I searched for something which does exactly what I want&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
